The accused is found innocent.
被告人無罪
Mr. Hiyama committed a crime.
緋山先生有犯罪
He committed murder!
他有殺人！
I struggle to understand where your sense of justice lies.
你對於正義的定義到底是什麼？ 我真的搞不懂
Seeing him save an innocent person,
看到拯救無辜之人的他後
I was inspired to be like him.
我也希望自己能變成那種人
I respect your decision.
我會尊重你的意志
However,
不過呢
just as you will stick to your sense of justice,
如同你會貫徹自己的正義
I will also follow my own path.
我也會在自己的道路上繼續前行
-Um… -Ms. Shiraki.
-那個… -白木小姐
Do you have the details regarding the Shinagawa injury case?
品川傷害事件的 現場資料準備齊全了嗎？
Um,
我想想
you mean Shoichiro Tomita's case, right?
你是指富田正一郎先生的案件吧？
I've placed them in the shared folder for the other two.
他們倆下午上班 我整理在共用資料夾了
I'll send them over later.
我等一下寄給你
I'll appreciate that.
謝謝
CLIENT: SHOICHIRO TOMITA
（委託人：富田正一郎）
I saw the news.
我有看到新聞
You've been appearing on TV a lot lately.
你最近常出現在電視上耶
It's a bit embarrassing for me, you know?
我看了都感到難為情
Could you at least shave cleanly?
你至少該把鬍子刮乾淨吧
Sorry about that.
不好意思
NPO DOG SHELTER WAN HAPPY
（非營利組織狗狗中途之家 汪快樂）
COURTHOUSE
（法院）
As stated in the indictment,
如同起訴狀記載的
this injury case took place on March 8th.
這次的傷害事件發生在3月8日
The location of the crime is the alley beside CLUB 1000 in Shinagawa Ward.
案發現場位在 品川區薩森德夜店的巷子內
The victim, Mr. Hirokazu Kudo, exited the club at 11:45 p.m.
被害人的工藤弘和先生 晚上11點45分走出店裡
Immediately afterward, a man shoved him from behind
下一瞬間突然有人從背後猛力推他
and assaulted him.
對他施暴
The assailant was wearing a hoodie and his face was concealed.
該男子用連帽上衣的帽子遮住臉
However, just before Mr. Kudo lost consciousness,
根據工藤先生的證詞
he claims to have seen the face of the accused, Shoichiro Tomita.
他在昏倒前看到被告富田正一郎的臉
The decision to indict the accused is supported by three factors.
這次是基於三個原因起訴被告
Firstly, the victim's testimony claims he identified the accused.
第一個原因是剛才描述的 被害者本人的目擊證詞
Secondly,
第二個原因是
there is evidence of a heated argument between the accused and Mr. Kudo.
被告與工藤先生發生過激烈的口角
My bad. Don't be so upset.
抱歉，你別生氣啦
You don't want to escalate this.
你不想引發糾紛吧
Especially for your daddy's sake.
為了你爸爸
Multiple testimonies from club customers support this claim.
我們已取得店內多位客人的證詞
We believe the accused's anger
對被害人言行舉止的惱怒
toward the victim's behavior motivated the assault.
是這次行使暴力的動機
We have also verified that there have been
我們也確認過被告與被害人之間
similar conflicts between the accused and the victim in the past.
以前發生過類似的糾紛
Finally, the third factor is the testimony provided by Mr. A.
最後的第三個原因
He was the first to arrive at the scene and also witnessed their argument.
看到兩人爭論的A先生的證詞
Mr. A saw the accused leaving shortly after Mr. Kudo did,
A先生表示有看到被告
seemingly following Mr. Kudo.
跟著走出店外的工藤先生離開
About three minutes later, when Mr. A left the club,
A先生在大約三分鐘後走到店外
he saw the accused heading toward the main street.
結果目擊被告走向大街
Suspecting that something might have occurred between the two,
A先生懷疑兩人之間出了什麼事
Mr. A headed in the direction the accused had come from.
於是朝被告出現的方向走
There, he found the victim who had been assaulted.
結果發現遭到毆打的被害人
-Are you okay? -Mr. A promptly called for an ambulance.
-你沒事吧？ -A先生立刻叫了救護車
And the victim was transported to the hospital.
將被害人送到醫院
Mr. A's call was made at 11:48 p.m.
他通話的時間是晚上11點48分
This is documented by the Fire Command Center.
消防指揮中心也有留下紀錄
Therefore, we believe the accused assaulted the victim
也就是說，被害人是在這三分鐘之間
within this three-minute window.
遭被告施暴
This concludes the prosecution's opening statement.
以上是檢方的開場陳述
Next,
那麼接下來
defense counsel, present your opening statement.
也請辯護人進行開場陳述
I, Akizumi, of the defense counsel, will deliver the opening statement.
我是辯護人明墨 由我來進行開場陳述
The accused acknowledges there was indeed an argument with the victim.
被告承認的確與被害人爭吵過
However, he maintains his innocence in this case.
不過他堅持 自己在這起案件中是無辜的
At the time of the incident…
案件發生時…
The accused received a call from his friend, Mr. Tomoya Kida,
被告的朋友木田智也先生 開車來接他
who had arrived to pick him up by car, and so left the club.
他接到朋友的電話後就離開夜店
He proceeded to the main street
直接走到大街上
and entered Mr. Kida's car parked by the shoulder.
坐上停在路邊的木田先生的車
They then headed directly to Mr. Kida's residence.
然後前往木田先生的家
Both of their smartphones have records of a call at 11:45 p.m.
兩人的手機中都有留下 晚上11點45分的通話紀錄
The club's security camera footage also captures the accused
店內的監視器
Mr. Kida has also testified
根據木田先生的證詞
that Mr. Shoichiro entered his car immediately after the call.
他也主張正一郎先生 講完電話後立刻就上車了
This concludes the proceedings scheduled for today.
那麼今天預定進行的程序都結束了
The focus will be on assessing the credibility of each testimony.
爭議點在於雙方的供述是否可信
Cross-examinations for each witness
下次開庭時按計劃
will proceed as scheduled in future trials.
進行雙方證人的交叉詢問
The son of Diet member Tomita, huh?
他是富田議員的兒子啊？
The public must be in an uproar.
會在世間引發大騷動吧
They thrive on scandals involving politicians and their children.
他們最愛跟政客小孩有關的醜聞了
But I disapprove of how the media
雖然媒體只在這種時候
only seems to push for power limitation during such episodes.
主張抑制權力的行為也不太好
Can you handle Attorney Akizumi?
對手是明墨律師，你沒問題嗎？
There's no need to worry.
不需要擔心
It's clear that Shoichiro Tomita has committed a crime.
富田正一郎確實犯了罪
Besides,
而且我不認同明墨律師的所作所為
To secure an acquittal for a murderer…
居然想讓殺人犯獲判無罪
That's something…
絕對不可以…
that should never be allowed, right?
讓那種事情發生，對吧？
Yes.
沒錯
DARK DONUT
（暗黑甜甜圈）
Is this okay?
沒問題嗎？
Here's your change and receipt.
這是找的錢和發票
-Thank you. -How's Mr. Akamine?
-謝謝惠顧 -赤峰先生還好嗎？
He seems conflicted about our policy.
他似乎對我們的方針感到困惑
He must have come here with his own agenda.
他是基於自己的意志來到這裡
You're right.
說得也是
I suppose we'll wait and see for now?
現在要先靜觀其變，是嗎？
Yes.
對
Tap your card.
請刷卡
-Thank you. -Mr. Matsunaga…
-謝謝惠顧 -松永先生…
Next in line, please.
排隊的下一位，請往前
-How would you like to pay? -By cash.
-要怎麼付款？ -我要付現
Mr. Kudo was shoved from behind into this alley.
工藤先生在這條巷子裡 被人從後方推倒
So, this is where he was assaulted.
他是在這附近被毆打
He sustained a compound fracture in his left arm.
我看看，他的左手臂複雜性骨折
Head injuries too.
頭部也有受傷
My apologies.
不好意思啊
I was occupied with another case and only saw the details this morning.
我因為其他案件比較晚參與 今天早上才看資料
Sorry, I didn't mean to sound accusing.
抱歉啦，我不是在指責你
I'll be heading inside first.
那麼我先進去了
Right.
好的
As mentioned in the report, there are no cameras outside.
如同調查記錄，外面沒有監視器
Mr. Kida's car was parked over there after a right turn.
前方右轉處就是木田先生停車的地方
There were no cameras capturing vehicles on that street either.
那條馬路上的監視器 也沒有拍到他的車子
Can you believe there are still cars without dashcams?
現在這個時代竟有人 沒裝行車記錄器，有可能嗎？
Can I see the cameras at Mr. Kida's apartment?
有辦法看木田先生 公寓的監視器畫面嗎？
Here.
在這邊
This is it.
就是這段
It's clear that Mr. Shoichiro and Mr. Kida passed through the lobby at midnight.
正一郎先生與木田先生 確實在凌晨十二點經過大廳
It's about a 15-minute drive to the apartment from here.
從這裡到公寓車程大約是15分鐘
If they left at 11:48 p.m., they'd have 12 minutes.
如果他是晚上11點48分出來 等於只花12分鐘就到了
They could compensate for the three minutes by rushing.
只要車開快一點 縮短3分鐘的時間不是問題
You know…
我要提醒你一下
Yes?
什麼事？
Mr. Shoichiro is the client.
我們的委託人可是正一郎先生
People who get to hang out here must be living it up.
來這種地方玩的人應該很享受人生吧
Are you jealous?
你很羨慕嗎？
No.
才沒有
That's a stereotype.
那是你的偏見
It's like assuming all attorneys are intelligent,
就像大家認為律師都很聰明
which isn't accurate.
實際上卻不是那樣
People might appear to be enjoying themselves.
當他們在這裡享樂時
But they could be concealing enough stress to snap
可能背負著龐大的壓力
and beat someone to death at any moment.
導致他們隨時都可能打死人
That's just how humans are.
人類就是這種生物
My apologies for the delay.
不好意思，讓各位久等了
Thank you for your time.
打擾你工作了，抱歉
I'm Mikami, the manager.
我是店長的三上
What brings you here today?
今天找我有什麼事？
The victim Mr. Kudo?
被害人的工藤先生？
Yes.
是的
We've heard he was verbally abusing Mr. Shoichiro Tomita.
我們聽說他辱罵過富田正一郎先生
Do you know if Mr. Kudo has been treating others in a similar manner?
工藤先生是否常對其他人做這種事？
He has.
你說對了
To be frank,
老實說啊
maybe because he runs his own company, he's quite proud.
那個人在經營公司，自尊心很高
It's not a large company though.
明明不是什麼大公司
Whenever he meets someone seemingly more important…
但只要看到比自己有權勢的人…
I'll try to collect more negative gossip about Mr. Kudo.
我去多蒐集一些 與工藤先生有關的負面流言
It could help undermine the credibility of motives and testimonies.
有助於打擊他的動機與證詞的可信度
Right.
好
Let's begin interviewing the regulars tomorrow.
明天開始去找常客問話吧
Mr. Akamine?
赤峰先生？
Um… right.
好的
Here's the information I've collected about Mr. Kudo over the past few days.
這是我最近查到的 工藤先生的相關情報
He's regarded by many CLUB 1000 customers as a troublemaker.
薩森德夜店的許多客人 都把他視為麻煩人物
They've testified that his verbal abuse
依他們的證詞 工藤先生平時就常口出惡言
There may be more than one person who holds a grudge against him.
可能有不少人對他懷恨在心
Akamine, do you have something to say?
赤峰，你有話想說嗎？
No.
沒有
I'll look into the crime scene further before the next trial.
在下次開庭前 我會進一步調查犯罪現場
If we can find information on the real culprit,
只要得到真凶的情報
it should greatly aid in solving this case.
就能一口氣解決這案子了
Right.
沒錯
You do that.
那就拜託你了
I will.
好的
The assault took place here…
受害人在這裡被毆打…
And Shoichiro got into the car here.
正一郎在此上車
But…
可是…
Lucky them.
好羨慕喔
This is the car.
就是這台車
It really doesn't have a dashcam.
果然沒有裝行車記錄器
Maybe it was removed after the incident.
不過可能是在事件後拆掉了
Who are you?
你是誰？
Well…
那個…
I was just admiring the car.
我想說這真是一台好車
Excuse me.
不好意思
You're still here.
你還在啊
I have to prepare for the defense team meeting next week
我還要準備下週食物中毒事件的
regarding the food poisoning case.
辯護律師團會議
You have a lot on your plate.
你真忙啊
So, any compelling evidence?
所以你有找到有力的證據嗎？
No.
不
I couldn't find any.
我沒找到
Mr. Akizumi and the prosecution have conducted investigations already.
明墨律師和檢方 已經進行許多調查了
-It's only natural that-- -Ms. Shinomiya…
-事到如今不太可能… -紫之宮小姐
Who do you think is the real culprit
你覺得這起事件
in this incident?
真正的犯人是誰？
We have the victim and Mr. A as two eyewitnesses.
有被害人與A先生這兩位目擊者
Are you saying Mr. Shoichiro did it?
你想說是正一郎先生幹的？
I'm saying simply exposing Mr. Kudo's personality
光是從工藤先生的人品分析
isn't substantial evidence.
不算是充足的證據
This is Mr. Akizumi. He must have a plan.
這可是明墨律師負責的 他一定有自己的考量
Ms. Shinomiya,
紫之宮小姐
why are you so obedient to him?
你為什麼總是對他唯命是從？
Because I want to understand his viewpoint better.
因為我想更了解他的想法
THE SECOND PUBLIC TRIAL
（第二次公審）
On the day of the incident,
案發當日
Mr. Shoichiro Tomita, the accused, claimed he was insulted by you.
被告富田正一郎先生說 你對他惡語相向
Is this true?
這是事實嗎？
No.
不是
The manager and regulars of CLUB 1000
根據薩森德夜店的店長與常客的證詞
have testified that you have previously caused disturbances with other customers.
你以前也跟其他客人發生過糾紛
Is this correct?
確定這是事實嗎？
I've been involved in some disagreements,
我多少有跟其他人發生口角
but I've never caused any big trouble.
但沒有引發大規模糾紛
A brief investigation revealed at least four incidents
我只是稍微查一下 就發現你在過去兩個月內
in the past two months.
和人爭執過四次
I don't recall.
我不記得了
You don't? Even though you caused them?
你不記得了？ 是你自己惹出來的案件吧？
Your Honor.
庭上
The intent behind his questions is unclear.
他發問的意圖太模糊了
Defense counsel, clarify the intent behind your questions.
請律師明確發問
You claim not to recall events from the past two months.
既然你不記得這兩個月發生的事
How then can you give a clear account of the incident from a month ago?
還有辦法明確陳述 一個月前發生的事件嗎？
I was assaulted.
我可是被人打了
It's natural that I remember that clearly.
當然清楚記得當初發生的事
The incident took place late at night.
此案是在深夜發生
Wasn't it dark?
周圍很暗吧？
There was light from the club.
夜店有開燈
And this light allowed you to see your assailant's face clearly?
因為店家有開燈 所以你有看清楚施暴者的臉？
That's right.
-對 -夜店的燈在哪裡？
In the alley beside the club.
店家旁邊的巷子裡
I see.
原來如此
Your Honor, to clarify the witness' statement,
庭上，為了讓證人的陳述更明確
I would like to present a video taken at the crime scene.
請容我播放在事件現場拍攝的影片
But the evidence hasn't been examined yet, right?
但證據調查尚未結束吧？
What is it?
是什麼樣的影片？
I received permission from Mr. Mikami, the manager of CLUB 1000,
這是薩森德夜店的店長 三上先生允許後
to recreate the situation of the crime scene at the time.
還原事件現場當下情況的影片
Prosecutor, your stance?
檢方怎麼看？
I will examine it, then provide my opinion.
我會在確認後回覆庭上
We filmed this at the same hour as when the incident occurred
在與事件當天同一時間
and recreated the situation.
重現當下狀況後拍攝了這段影片
The camera replicates the perspective of Mr. Kudo, the victim.
拍攝角度與被害人 工藤先生的視角相同
Mr. Kudo, after leaving the club,
工藤先生，你走出夜店後
you walked toward the alley, is that correct?
就彎進巷子了吧？
Yes.
對
You claimed you saw the accused's face at this moment.
你聲稱當時有看到被告的長相
Wait.
等一下
It wasn't this dark when I was assaulted.
我被攻擊時燈光沒有這麼昏暗
There was a light!
當時有開燈！
There was indeed a motion sensor light at the crime scene.
現場確實裝有感應式照明
However, according to Mr. Mikami, the manager,
但我問過店長的三上先生
on the night of the incident, the light was broken and didn't work.
他說事件發生當晚 感應燈故障了，並未啟動
That's impossible!
不可能！
It was clearly noted on the fixture list as well.
備品的交換清單上也有寫
Three days after the incident, the sensor light was replaced.
在事件發生的三天後更換了感應燈
That's too convenient…
那樣未免也太…
A moment, please.
請等一下
It may not have been as dark when the incident took place.
案件發生當天的昏暗程度 不一定跟影片中相同
But you can't prove it was brighter either, can you?
但你也無法證明 現場到底有多明亮吧？
I saw what I saw!
我就是有看到！
This man assaulted me!
是這傢伙打了我！
By the way, what color is the hoodie worn by the man playing the culprit?
順便問一下，你還記得 嫌犯穿著什麼顏色的連帽上衣嗎？
Huh?
什麼？
It's black.
黑色
Are you sure?
真的嗎？
Our perception can be deceiving.
人的眼睛會產生錯覺
And memories are shaped by bias and preconceptions.
記憶也會因偏見與成見而遭竄改
If we're not careful,
一個不小心
we could invent a culprit who's actually innocent.
也可能讓無辜的人成為罪犯
We're back.
我們回來了
-We're back. -Welcome back.
-我們回來了 -辛苦了
If you had told me, I could've assisted as well.
你該跟我說一聲，那我就可以幫忙
Mr. Akizumi wanted to let you focus on your other case.
因為明墨律師顧慮到你在忙其他案件
-And let Mr. Akamine investigate too. -No.
-赤峰先生也想自己調查吧 -不對
Mr. Akizumi…
明墨律師
Will you secure another acquittal for a criminal?
你又打算幫犯人脫罪嗎？
about that video in advance.
那支影片的事
That's because Mr. Mikami was bribed to testify in your favor, right?
是因為你買通了夜店店長的三上先生 要他做假的證言吧？
When the crime took place,
案發當時
the light should've been working fine.
照明燈應該無異常，是明亮的狀態
But…
然而…
Seiji Tomita paid him off
富田誠二用錢堵他的嘴
to testify in our favor, didn't he?
讓對方說出對我們 有利的證詞，對吧？
Seiji Tomita?
富田誠二？
You mean Mr. Shoichiro's father?
是指正一郎先生的父親？
And to conceal that,
你為了隱瞞這件事
you kept the video from us.
刻意不告訴我們這支影片的存在
The fixture list too.
那張備品清單也一樣
Shoichiro probably bribed him to make their stories match.
正一郎絕對為了串供而給了錢
Even the car had a dashcam,
而且車上本來有裝行車記錄器吧
but you told him to remove it!
因為對我方不利 所以你指使他拆掉了！
Hmm.
是喔
That's a good theory, fitting for an attorney.
這是很像律師會做出的優秀假設
And…
然後…
what's your basis?
你的依據是什麼？
It resembles the previous incident.
因為上次的案件就是這樣
Previous?
上次？
Before joining this office…
來這間事務所之前…
I was assigned to Shoichiro Tomita's injury case.
我負責過富田正一郎的傷害事件
But even then,
但那時也一樣
his father, a member of the Diet, used money to cover up his son's crime.
兒子的罪行 全靠當國會議員的父親用錢擺平
It was a case of injury, much like this one.
是跟這次一樣的傷害案件
Stop it!
快住手！
You're going too far!
沒必要做到那種地步！
I tried desperately to stop him!
我當時拼命阻止他！
It wasn't me.
我不是犯人
It was Shoichiro!
是正一郎做的啊！
The next day, the police showed up at my home
但警察隔天出現在我家
and suddenly arrested me.
突然逮捕我
Everyone who was there said I did it!
所有在場者都指控我有打人！
Later, one of his friends told me
後來他的一位朋友告訴我
that Shoichiro's father was throwing money around
正一郎的父親用錢買通周遭的人
to make the people involved change their testimonies.
要求他們改變證詞
But the friend was too scared to come forward and testify.
不過他太害怕，不敢作證
That's why…
所以…
No. Try to get a lesser sentence.
行不通，朝減刑的方向處理吧
Why?
為什麼？
Because we're dealing with the son of a politician?
因為對方是政治家的兒子嗎？
Shoichiro is the one who did it!
是正一郎動的手！
The office I worked at was put under pressure,
他向我隸屬的事務所施壓
and I was removed from the case.
我被迫退出那個案子
The decision.
主文
The accused is sentenced to two years in prison.
判處被告兩年有期徒刑
The execution of the sentence will be suspended for five years
從宣讀判決的這一天起
from the day it becomes final.
執行緩刑五年
Wait!
請等一下！
Mr. Matsunaga is innocent!
松永先生是無辜的！
Spectator, quiet down.
旁聽人，請保持安靜
Your Honor, please review this document.
庭上，請看看這份資料
I order him to leave!
命令他立刻退庭！
They'll use money to cover up anything inconvenient to them.
只要狀況對自己不利 就用錢解決問題
That's what politicians do.
那就是政治家的手段
Shoichiro is using his father and laughing about it as we speak.
正一郎利用了父親 現在也得意洋洋地笑著
You're aware that Seiji Tomita is making people change their testimonies,
你明明知道富田誠二讓證人改變供述
and yet you took on this case.
卻還是接下了此案件
What's your purpose?
你有什麼目的？
That's why you started the investigation
所以你才打從一開始
I understand your point.
我理解你的主張了
But that's not a theory. It's just wild fancy.
但那不是假設，只是妄想罷了
Baseless fancy doesn't hold up in the legal world.
沒有任何依據的妄想 在司法的世界並不管用
Do you have evidence that Seiji Tomita was distributing money?
你說富田誠二買通證人，有證據嗎？
Or that Mr. Mikami accepted the money
你說三上先生收了錢
and altered his testimony to fit the narrative?
進行了串供，有證據嗎？
Well…
這個嘛…
If you can't substantiate your claims with evidence, it's just baloney.
如果你無法佐證
The fact that Mr. Matsunaga was convicted
松永先生會被判有罪
isn't the fault of Japan's justice system, your law office, the court,
錯不在日本司法、事務所或是法院
or even Diet member Tomita.
以及富田議員
It's on you as the defense counsel.
而是你這個律師的責任
The outcome of a trial decides the fate of the client.
審判的結果會左右委託人的人生
That's why we attorneys must dedicate our lives to winning them.
所以我們身為律師 必須賭上自己的人生
You simply lacked the commitment and skills necessary.
你這個人沒有那份覺悟與實力
Mr. Matsunaga was condemned to bear guilt because of you.
是你害松永先生背負罪名
No matter how much you may regret it,
不管你有多後悔
the fact that he was labeled a criminal will never fade away.
依然抹除不了他成為罪犯的事實
If you can't come to terms with this case,
如果你沒辦法接受
you're free to step away.
可以退出這個案子
I won't.
我不要
If I uncover clear evidence of Shoichiro's crime
在審理結束前
what will happen then?
到時候怎麼辦？
Interesting.
真有趣
It's against an attorney's regulations to knowingly collaborate with a client
如果我們知道委託人 做出違法性高的虛偽供述
If you can uncover that Mr. Shoichiro was lying,
若我們能發現正一郎先生在說謊
I would also appreciate that.
對我來說也是好事一樁
However…
不過呢
only if such evidence exists.
前提是你要找到證據
They probably collaborated with the club to work behind the scenes.
他們一定跟店家同謀，動了手腳
It's an affront to a fair trial.
根本在冒瀆審判的公正性
Who knows?
天曉得
But let's refrain from speculating.
別討論這種臆測了
What matters is presenting evidence.
重點是要找出相關證據
Should I look into what's happening with Manager Mikami?
我該去查一下三上店長的背景嗎？
Reinvestigate the testimonies of the customers instead.
你再調查一次客人的證詞吧
Excuse me.
不好意思
There was an injury case in that alley on March 8th.
那條巷子在3月8日發生了傷害事件
Do you recall anything?
你們有記得的事嗎？
Please, at least take the flyer!
請等一下，至少收下傳單吧！
There was an injury case in that alley late at night on March 8th…
3月8日的深夜 那條巷子發生了傷害事件…
HIROMACHI RIVER
（廣町川）
HARAGUROYA
（腹黑屋）
It's bad enough that my son has been indicted.
兒子遭起訴已經是大事了
And if he ends up being convicted too…
如果被判有罪就更糟了
All I've asked of him is to stay out of trouble,
我老是叮嚀他選區會由他哥哥繼承
saying I'd have his older brother take over my activities.
只要別惹麻煩就好
But did he listen?
真受不了那傢伙
The naughtier the child, the dearer they become, they say.
世人都說愛闖禍的孩子更討人喜歡
Here.
請喝
I shelled out a hefty sum on his education from elementary to university.
從小學到大學 我為他花了高昂的學費
Maybe I should've been tougher on him.
當初應該更嚴格地教育他
He's such a handful.
真讓人困擾
But there's no issue with this case.
但這次的案件完全不用擔心
Your son is innocent, after all.
因為令郎沒有犯罪
Can we trust you on that?
我們可以相信你吧？
We've pretty much demolished the victim's eyewitness testimony.
被害人的目擊證詞等於被推翻了
We just have to handle the other witness, but we'll get it done.
剩下另一位證人，我們也會處理好
Well,
天啊
I made the right call in hiring you.
看來委託你是正確的決定
Thank you.
謝謝
However,
不過有件事讓我有些在意
What about?
什麼事？
It's not a big deal, but…
雖然不是什麼大事…
HIROMACHI RIVERSIDE SHINAGAWA WARD
（品川區廣町川路）
Planning to stay longer?
你還會待很久嗎？
Yeah.
對
I'll make sure to lock up.
我下班前會記得鎖門窗
Thanks.
麻煩你囉
Good night.
辛苦了
HARAGUROYA
（腹黑屋）
He was here until late last night again.
他昨天也加班到很晚
I wonder what he's up to.
不知道在做什麼
Piping work at fifth street Naka-shinagawa?
中品川五丁目的配管工程？
Yes. On the night of March 8th,
是的，我正在尋找3月8日晚上
there was this truck at the site. I'm trying to find it.
停在這個施工現場的卡車
That's our vehicle.
這是我們的車
-Could you come with me? -Sure.
-可以跟我來一下嗎？ -好的
It seems there was a faulty pipe, and they rushed over to address it.
管線中好像有零件故障 所以他當天趕到那裡
How long did it stay there?
卡車在那裡停了多久？
According to the records,
他的下班時間
it came back at 6:30 a.m. the following morning.
是隔天早上6點30分
So I assume it was there the entire night.
大概整晚都停在那裡吧
I see.
這樣啊
Does the vehicle have a dashcam?
那輛車有裝行車記錄器嗎？
Of course, it does.
當然有
There's footage in that camera that could provide crucial evidence for a case.
行車記錄器的影像中
Could you please show me this data?
可以讓我看一下影片的檔案嗎？
ATTORNEY SHUTO AKAMINE
（律師，赤峰柊斗）
The data?
檔案？
You're back. How did your search go?
你回來啦，有找到東西嗎？
Huh? What's up with him?
幹嘛？怎麼了？
You concealed the evidence.
你把證據藏起來了吧
There must be footage of Shoichiro getting into Kida's car.
有段影片拍到正一郎上木田的車
On the day of the incident,
案發當日
the main street where Kida parked his car was undergoing piping work.
木田的車所停靠的大街 正在進行配管工程
However, there was a faulty equipment, and this truck was sent there.
但當天有人碰巧被叫去處理故障零件 就是這輛卡車
Don't you have the data?
請問檔案有保留下來嗎？
I already handed it over to the other attorney.
檔案已經交給律師了
ATTORNEY MASAKI AKIZUMI
（律師，明墨正樹）
I'm impressed you figured it out.
你竟然發現了啊
Please show me the footage.
請讓我看影片
Is there a reason you can't?
不能讓我看嗎？
The footage should show Shoichiro entering Kida's car at 11:48 p.m.,
就是正一郎走出夜店的三分鐘後 晚上11點48分
three minutes after he left the club.
坐上木田的車的影片
If this gets out,
只要影片曝光
you'll lose the trial, won't you?
我們就會輸掉官司吧？
Fine.
我知道了
I'll show you.
給你看吧
Let me fast forward a bit.
那我快轉喔
That's Kida's car, right?
這是木田的車吧？
Right.
對
This is the time the crime occurred,
犯案的時間
at 11:45 p.m.
是晚上11點45分
See?
看吧
He's not showing up.
他果然沒有出現
He came.
他來了
As he testified, at 11:45 p.m.,
如同證詞，就在晚間11點45分
Mr. Shoichiro arrived.
正一郎先生現身了
Do you have any issues with the footage?
這支影片有什麼問題嗎？
What about…
那麼…
Mr. A's testimony of seeing Shoichiro leave the club?
A先生離開店裡後 看到正一郎的證詞是怎麼回事？
That would be false.
那是謊言
Why?
為什麼？
Hiroshi Yamanobe.
山野邊宏
That's the name of the man known as witness Mr. A.
這是目擊者A先生的名字
That day, Yamanobe witnessed an argument between the two inside the club.
山野邊那天在店裡看到兩人在吵架
He saw this as an opportunity
覺得這是一個好機會
because he was among those who held a grudge against the victim.
因為他也是 看被害人不順眼的其中一人
Upon seeing the victim and Mr. Shoichiro leave the club,
他看到被害人與正一郎先生走出店外
he immediately followed them to frame Mr. Shoichiro.
為了將罪行栽贓給正一郎先生 立刻跟著走出去
He then assaulted Mr. Kudo.
並對工藤先生施暴
Hold on a moment.
請等一下
But he left three minutes after they did.
但他說是在兩人離開的 三分鐘後才走出夜店
That would also be false.
那也是謊言
The camera should show Yamanobe leaving right after the two.
行車記錄器應該有拍到兩人離開後 山野邊跟著走出店外的畫面
But…
怎麼可能
Well, the prosecution tends to ignore evidence that's inconvenient to them.
檢方本來就會無視對他們不利的證據
After Yamanobe assaulted Mr. Kudo,
山野邊施暴後
he played innocent and pretended to be the first person at the scene,
若無其事地假冒成第一發現者
then called an ambulance.
叫了救護車
At least,
但這只是我虛構的故事罷了
Did you ever stop to consider this possibility?
你曾思考過這種可能性嗎？
Maybe it's due to your previous trial,
我不知道你以前的官司是什麼狀況
but you're fixated on this individual, Shoichiro Tomita.
但你太執著於富田正一郎這個人
Because of personal resentment,
你對他的恨意
you're unquestionably accepting the prosecution's narrative.
使你對檢方所描述的 另一個虛構故事毫不懷疑
You're overlooking objective facts
看漏客觀的事實
and attempting to convict this person.
企圖加諸罪名在那個人身上
Your actions are no different from those of a criminal.
你所做的事情跟罪犯沒兩樣
In fact,
確切來說
your knowledge of the law makes your actions even worse.
因為你懂法知法 使這樣的行為更加惡劣
Deep-seated prejudices
太深的成見
and a half-hearted commitment to justice lead to flawed judgments.
以及半吊子的正義感 會讓人失去判斷能力
People like you end up making false accusations.
就是你這樣的人會導致冤獄發生
THE THIRD PUBLIC TRIAL
（第三次公審）
I, Prosecutor Midorikawa, will ask some questions.
先由我，檢察官的綠川提問
According to evidence number 8, as requested by the defense counsel,
根據辯方請求證據第8號
you picked up the accused in your car at 11:45 p.m.
被告上你的車的時間是晚上11點45分
Is that correct?
沒有錯吧？
Yes.
對
Could it have been…
他上車前
after the assault took place?
有可能對人施暴嗎？
That's impossible.
不可能
I made the call at 11:45 p.m.,
我在晚上11點45分打電話後
and Shoichiro arrived right after that.
正一郎立刻就來了
The call records have been presented as well.
我也有提供通話紀錄
Are you sure it was immediately afterward?
他真的立刻就上車了嗎？
Is it possible you're mistaken?
會不會是你誤會了？
Objection.
有異議
Repetitive questioning.
提問重複了
Objection sustained.
認同異議
Prosecutor, please pose a different inquiry.
請檢方改變問題
Your Honor,
庭上
to refresh the witness' memory,
為了喚起證人的記憶
I would like to present new evidence and pose questions.
我想讓證人確認 最新取得的影片再進行訊問
May I proceed?
可以嗎？
I was unable to disclose it in advance as it was acquired late.
因為太晚取得這個證據 沒辦法事前開示
However,
不過呢
this footage is pivotal to the trial.
這是審理本案不可或缺的影片
I ask that you permit this.
可以請庭上允許嗎？
What is the content of this footage?
是什麼樣的影片？
It captures the location
那段影片拍到
where Mr. Kida's car was parked
案發當天木田先生
on the day of the incident.
停車的地方
Very well.
我知道了
Defense counsel, your stance?
辯護人有什麼意見？
I defer to your judgment, Your Honor.
遵從庭上的判斷
On the day of the incident,
這是案發當日
at the main street where the witness claimed to have picked up the accused,
證人聲稱讓被告上車的大街
there was ongoing piping work.
當時在進行配管工程
This footage is from the dashcam of the truck stationed at that site.
這是當時停在路邊的卡車 裡頭行車記錄器拍下的影片
Mr. Kida, can you confirm that this is indeed your car?
木田先生，這是你的車沒錯吧？
Yes, it is.
沒錯
It's 11:45 p.m., the time stated by the witness.
證人主張的晚上11點45分到了
However, the accused has not yet arrived.
但被告還沒出現
It's now 11:48 p.m.
時間來到晚間的11點48分
This aligns with Mr. A's statement
此情況符合證人A所描述的內容
that he exited the club at 11:48 p.m. and saw Mr. Shoichiro.
在48分離開夜店並目睹正一郎先生
Moments ago, you asserted
你剛剛斷言
that you picked up the accused at 11:45 p.m.
曾讓被告在晚間11點45分上車
How do you explain this, Mr. Kida?
木田先生，這是怎麼回事？
Perhaps the accused…
事情的真相就是
requested you to provide a false testimony?
被告其實拜託你偽造證詞，對吧？
That's not true.
沒有那種事
Objection.
有異議
The prosecutor's statement is merely speculative.
剛才那番話只是檢方的臆測
Objection sustained.
認同異議
Your Honor, there is a crucial issue that I would like to discuss
庭上，我有一件重要事項
What is it about?
什麼事項？
It pertains to the false testimony mentioned just now.
與方才的偽證發言相關
I would like to discuss whether it's feasible…
該事項是否能在法庭公布…
to disclose this matter during this session.
我需要跟你們討論一下
I will now play the recently added evidence,
那麼我將播放新添加的
evidence number 20, as requested by the prosecution.
檢方請求證據甲字第20號
This was provided by Mr. Gamo from the pipe manufacturing company,
這是剛剛提供影片的
who also supplied the video I previously presented.
管線製造公司的蒲生先生所寄來的
Please watch the video.
請過目
-Please, have a seat. -Thank you.
-這邊請，請坐 -打擾了
Here.
來
Let me cut to the chase.
我直接切入正題了，請收下
This is your reward for providing us with the dashcam footage.
這是你提供行車記錄器影片的謝禮
But I can't--
我不能收…
There's no need to fret.
不需要擔心
Even if the prosecution comes knocking,
萬一檢察官找上門
all you have to do is tell them you didn't keep any records.
希望你能告訴對方 你們沒有留下任何紀錄
The truth is, this has happened before.
其實過去也發生過同樣的狀況
But if you accept this,
只要你能收下
everything will fall into place.
這件事就能圓滿收場了
Mr. Tomita can also orchestrate things in your business's favor.
議員今後在工作上 也會給貴公司特別待遇
I trust you'll--
以後請多指教…
The visitor is the chief publicly paid secretary
與他見面的人是眾議院議員
to Mr. Seiji Tomita, a member of the House of Representatives.
富田誠二先生的公設第一祕書 小杉和昭先生
From this,
這足以證明
This serves as proof that he requested
富田誠二先生利用了祕書
the concealment of evidence through his secretary.
委託他人隱匿證據
Defense counsel,
辯護人
do you have any rebuttal to offer?
針對此事，你要進行反駁嗎？
After viewing the footage,
看到影片後
I was utterly shocked.
我簡直不敢相信
I had no idea that the accused…
沒想到被告
had conspired with his father
竟然跟父親串通好
to conceal his crime!
企圖隱匿犯罪行為！
Regarding this matter,
關於這件事
I will conduct further interviews.
我會再次詢問被告
And even consider…
並且會視情況
resigning from the defense depending on the situation.
考慮辭去辯護人的職務
I'll handle the media, so I'll go ahead.
我還要應付媒體，先走了
Mr. Akizumi.
明墨律師
That footage--
關於提供的影片…
You exposed my client's false testimony.
謝謝你揭露委託人的謊言
Thank you.
我向你道謝
I don't understand.
這是怎麼回事？
When I saw the footage,
我看影片時
Shoichiro got into the car at 11:45 p.m.
正一郎確實是在45分上車
The footage we were shown yesterday…
我們昨天看到的影片
was edited and false.
是經過剪輯的造假影片
There we go.
把這邊處理一下
Why do such a thing?
為什麼要做那種事？
I'm surprised he went to such lengths for you.
沒想到他會為了你做到這種地步
Hello?
喂？
Explain yourself, Akizumi!
你是在搞什麼？明墨！
It became clear you attempted to conceal your son's crime.
你企圖隱匿兒子罪行的事曝光了
That is all.
只是這樣而已
I can't continue defending a client who provides false testimony.
既然你們騙了我 我沒辦法繼續為他辯護了
But you instructed me to!
當初是你指示的吧！
However, I'm concerned about something.
不過有件事讓我有些在意
What about?
什麼事？
It's not a big deal, but…
雖然不是什麼大事…
It appears that Mr. Kida's car, which picked up Mr. Shoichiro,
其實木田先生開車去接正一郎先生時
was recorded by a dashcam at the construction site.
施工現場的行車記錄器 似乎拍到了他的車
It seems a truck belonging to a piping dealer was stationed there.
聽說是一間管線業者的卡車停在那裡
The prosecution isn't stupid.
檢方不是笨蛋
I believe it's only a matter of time before they uncover that footage.
他們找到那支影片只是時間的問題
Which dealer is it?
哪一間公司？
Tanimachi Pipes.
谷町管線公司
That's what you said!
都是因為你那麼說
That's why I instructed Kosugi!
我才會吩咐小杉！
Do you have any proof?
你有證據嗎？
What?
你說什麼？
Why would I instruct you to buy the footage from them?
我不可能要求你 用錢搶走那支影片吧？
You're the one who also made them record that footage!
看來那支影片也是你派人拍下的！
I don't know what you're talking about.
我不知道你在說什麼
I'm pressed for time, so please excuse me.
我在趕時間，再見
Hey! Akizumi!
喂！明墨！
-Mr. Tomita!
-富田議員！
Is my dad all right?
我爸還好嗎？
Are you worried about him?
你這麼擔心他？
He's still my father.
他畢竟算是我父親
The parent-child bond is just a facade.
親子關係只是表象罷了
Children don't get to choose their parents.
兒女無法選擇父母
But you can choose…
不過你的人生
what you do with your own life.
可以由你自己做選擇
In the trial for the injury case involving the accused Shoichiro Tomita,
被告的富田正一郎過去持續否認罪行
he has now admitted to his involvement, which he had previously denied.
但在這次審理時首次承認有出手傷人
The prosecution is also emphasizing that his father, Diet member Seiji Tomita,
此外檢方表示
Please review these.
麻煩你確認
It's all about Tomita, isn't it?
一直在報富田的新聞呢
After all, he was the candidate for the next Minister of Justice.
畢竟他是下一任法務大臣的熱門人選
I just can't wrap my head around it.
我實在搞不懂
Why did Mr. Akizumi…
為什麼明墨律師
show me the edited footage?
要讓我看造假的影片？
Last time, you were shouting from the gallery.
因為你上次在旁聽席大聲嚷嚷
The gallery?
-旁聽席？ -庭上
I order him to leave!
命令他立刻退庭！
we were present too.
我們也在場
Mr. Akizumi was present?
明墨律師也在？
Hold on, did Mr. Akizumi take on this case
所以說
Who can say?
我也不清楚
But I imagine he wanted to make a point.
但他大概是希望你能學到
To not confuse the truth with personal biases alone.
別因個人的一己之念而誤判真相
Where's Mr. Akizumi?
明墨律師在哪裡？
You've taken down not only the son, but also his father.
沒想到不只是兒子
I made the right call entrusting this to you.
交給你處理果然是正確的決定
Thank you.
謝謝
The downfall of Tomita, who belonged to the Takemoto faction,
竹本派的富田失勢
will likely please Mr. Kazaki from the Okuda faction.
這樣奧田派的加崎議員應該會很開心
Power struggles are scary, aren't they?
權力鬥爭真可怕，是吧？
It's been a while, Judge Seko.
好久不見，瀨古判事
Chief Prosecutor Datehara,
伊達原檢事正
it's unusual to see you here.
難得你會來到這裡
Prosecutor Midorikawa, you handled this case commendably.
綠川檢察官，你的表現很優秀
It's just like you to expose a politician's misdeeds.
揭發政治家的惡行確實很有你的風格
Thank you.
謝謝
I imagine you're both busy, but I wish you the best of luck.
兩位應該很忙碌吧，好好加油
Excuse me.
再見
I apologize.
對不起
You were aware of Mr. Matsunaga and Shoichiro
你打從一開始
from the beginning.
就知道松永先生和正一郎的事吧
You were right.
正如你所說的
I'd been looking at things assuming Shoichiro was guilty.
我在進行各種判斷時 預先認定正一郎有犯罪
It was inappropriate conduct for an attorney.
身為一個律師 我實在不該做出這行為
Well, he ended up being guilty, though.
不過他確實有犯罪
Regarding Mr. Matsunaga's case…
關於松永先生的事件…
I haven't given up yet.
我還沒有放棄
I'll find incriminating evidence on Shoichiro no matter what
我絕對會逮到正一郎的有罪證據
and pursue a retrial.
聲請再審
That's why you came to this office, right?
那就是你來我們事務所的目的吧？
Yes.
是的
I heard you took on Shoichiro's defense,
我聽說你要為正一郎辯護後
which is why I joined this office.
決定進入這間事務所
I wanted to learn your methods
我想學習你的辯護方式
and help Mr. Matsunaga.
幫助松永先生
But…
但是…
there are some things I struggle to accept.
我不認同你一部分的行事作風
So I'll stay here and continue to confirm things for myself.
所以我今後也會待下去 仔細去辨別好壞
To understand…
觀察你是出於什麼目的…
why you secure acquittals for criminals.
讓罪犯獲判無罪
I told you.
我告訴過你
Follow your own path.
你朝自己想走的道路前進就好
2021, 2020, 2019…
2021、2020、2019…
Ms. Shiraki, aren't there any records before this?
白木小姐，沒有更久以前的資料嗎？
Why the interest in past case files?
你為何在找過去案件的檔案？
I just…
我只是…
wanted to learn what makes Mr. Akizumi so skilled.
想知道明墨律師的實力有多強
You're quite enthusiastic.
你真是充滿熱誠啊
But this is all we have.
但那些就是全部的檔案了
This office was established only five years ago.
我們事務所是在五年前設立的
And Mr. Akizumi wasn't an attorney before that.
他在那之前並不是律師
Really? What was he doing?
真的嗎？他之前在做什麼？
He was a prosecutor.
檢察官
Mr. Shimizu, it's time.
志水先生，可以離開房間了
Right.
是
Mr. Shimizu.
志水先生
It's a pleasure…
我終於…
to finally meet you.
見到你了
Subtitle translation by: Ai Matsuoka
字幕翻譯：劉哲琪
Now, who should we bring down first?
現在要先擊潰哪一邊呢？
Do you have an appointment?
有事先約好嗎？
It's difficult to speak out against sex crimes.
性犯罪的被害者很難出面發聲
It wasn't me.
不是我做的
Is he planning another dramatic move?
又打算有高調的舉動了？
It seems he's beginning to realize.
他似乎察覺到了
You must pluck the tasty fruit yourself.
必須親手摘下甜美的果實
Maybe he has a purpose this time as well.
這次可能也有什麼目的
-Impossible. -Mr. Akizumi is trying to use me.
-不會吧 -明墨律師打算利用我